<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>NMBA</title>
  <subtitle>Northside Minor Basketball Association</subtitle>
  <id>http://northsidehoops.com/blog</id>
  <link href="http://northsidehoops.com/blog"/>
  <link href="http://northsidehoops.com/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2014-07-01T21:00:00-03:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Blog Author</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>NMBA To Build Through Steve Nash Program</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/07/02/nmba-to-build-through-snyb"/>
    <id>http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/07/02/nmba-to-build-through-snyb</id>
    <published>2014-07-01T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-07-02T23:45:02-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The NMBA is preparing for another season of Steve Nash Youth Basketball. Steve Nash Youth Basketball is Canada's national youth basketball initiative designed to develop fundamental skills, sportsmanship and a love of the game for basketball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Northside Minor Basketball Association certainly endorses the Nash program and is preparing for its third year of operation for the 2014-15 season. This grassroots program will support and empower minor associations, schools and local service clubs across New Brunswick in an effort to positively influence youth through basketball.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of the program is to allow participants the opportunity to maximize their potential, while promoting the importance of youth basketball as a vehicle to build character, discipline and self-esteem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model for Steve Nash Youth Basketball was established after extensive research of existing community basketball programs from across North America and follows the guidelines of Sport Canada's Long Term Athlete Development Model (LTAD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program is flexible in nature to allow local organizers to adapt the program and implement it in their community while following its principles and philosophies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="participant-benefits"&gt;Participant Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Participation in a national and provincial sanctioned basketball program.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Certified coaching by New NCCP trained coaches.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Steve Nash Youth Basketball Reversible Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Molton Rubber Basketball .&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Drawstring back-pack.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Partcipant certificate and poster.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Steve Nash Youth Basketball Parent's Guide.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Canada Basketball national membership.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Basketball New Brunswick provincial membership.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Insurance Coverage (via BNB membership)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="coaches-benefits"&gt;Coaches Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Canada Basketball and Coaching Association of Canada sanctioned clinics using the new NCCP Community Coach Model and curriculum&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;3-hour on-court Community Coach workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Steve Nash Youth Basketball Coaching CD Workbook&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Steve Nash Youth Basketball Coach's T-shirt, whistle and lanyard&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An introductory guide to the LTAD model&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Canada Basketball national membership&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Access to extensive and qualified coaching resources&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Basketball New Brunswick provincial membership&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Insurance Coverage (via BNB membership)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="local-organization-benefits"&gt;Local Organization Benefits&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Endorsement and affiliation with Steve Nash, Canada Basketball, Basketball New Brunswick and Sport Canada&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use of Steve Nash images and brand to communicate his values and commitment.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A comprehensive national and provincial marketing campaign and advertising strategy that will assist in the promotion and recruitment of participants and coaches for the program.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A step-by-step Steve Nash Youth Basketball operations guide.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Integration of your organization with Canada Basketball and Basketball New Brunswick programming.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id="info"&gt;Info&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The registration fee for 2014-15 season is expected to be in the range of $100 for children in K-1 and $150 for the season for those in Grade 2 and 3 and Grade 4 and 5. Information for the 2014-15 sessions will be released soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NMBA operates developmental Basketball New Brunswick teams at the mini, bantam and midget age class levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact the NMBA at nmbageneral@live.com for Nash information or how to sign up for development teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 2013-14 season, four players from the Nash program earned roster spots with NMBA teams.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Filipino Hoop Tournament Set For Saint John</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/06/25/filipino-hoop-tournament-set-for-saint-john"/>
    <id>http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/06/25/filipino-hoop-tournament-set-for-saint-john</id>
    <published>2014-06-24T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-25T15:30:55-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When:		July 6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where:	Bayside Middle School&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A one-day Filipino basketball tournament is being hosted in Saint John on July 6 at Bayside Middle School.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are currently eight teams registered from all over New Brunswick: Shediac, Fredericton, St. George, Deer Island, Woodstock and Saint John.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time this event has been held.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, email Earl Jen Basuel at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;earl.jen@unb.ca
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lions Prepare for First Ever Eastern Canadian Trek</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/06/23/lions-prepare-for-first-ever-eastern-canadian-trek"/>
    <id>http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/06/23/lions-prepare-for-first-ever-eastern-canadian-trek</id>
    <published>2014-06-22T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-23T11:23:49-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Bantam A Girls Division 1 Champs" src="../../../../../images/2014.nmba.d1.champs.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems like an awful long time ago. Mainly because it was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just past three months to the day, the Northside Minor Basketball Association Lions captured the first Bantam Division 1 Girls' Championship, the team prepares for a major opportunity this week. The Lions became the first NMBA team to qualify for the Eastern Canadian Championship which unfolds at the Canada Games Centre in Halifax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Competition begins June 27, culminating with champions being crowned June 29. The tournament has girls and boys at the under-14 and under-13 divisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NMBA squad features 11 players, nine of them first year bantam players. Many had anticipated the Lions would challenge for an under-13 spot, but after winning the Basketball New Brunswick championship last March, away they go. 'It's been a long process from gearing our entire season toward that weekend in March,' said Lions' head coach Ryan Chase. 'What people perhaps didn't realize was everything we did from October up until championship weekend was to prepare for that Sunday. That was from practice to game selection to roster planning to about anything else you can imagine. The girls responded.'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the championship, Chase gave the entire team almost six weeks off to pursue other sports and prepare for June. The team has played a number of exhibition games over the past month, but has only been together with a full complement of players once.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That will change Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lions open against Newfoundland champion Square Up of St. John's on June 27 at 3:30 p.m. NMBA then faces Goulds of Newfoundland at 8 p.m. at the sparkling three-court facility. On June 28, there's a familiar foe as NMBA faces the Kennebecasis Valley Slammers at 11:30 a.m. at Mount St. Vincent's University. Depending on their record, the schedule will unfold for the Lions either later June 28 or into semifinals June 29. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;'It's going to be challenging where it's been so long, but the girls have retained what they've been taught all season,' said Chase, who is also head coach of the BNB under-15 boys' team preparing for nationals in late July. 'We have to ensure the girls don't get caught up in the excitement of playing at this level for the first time. Our mindset all year was 'it's just another game, just another team, just another challenge,' and that has to unfold again in Halifax. Our leaders need to lead, our scorers need to score and each and everyone of the players needs to defend.'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lauren Casey and Maegan Burtt are the two graduating players on the Lions' squad as they will say goodbye to the minor basketball system following the tournament, preparing to move into Leo Hayes High School in the fall. The Grade 7 players include Lucy Beaumont, Chantelle Austin, Torrie Janes, Jaiden Penney, Kali Wilson, Katie Morehouse, Abby Cartwright, Erin O'Shaughnessy and Erin Cunningham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow results of the Lions on &lt;a href="http://www.twitter.com/NMBALIONS"&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; and Facebook as the tournament unfolds.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Former NMBA Lions Headed To ACAA Teams</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/06/19/former-nmba-lions-headed-to-acaa-teams"/>
    <id>http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/06/19/former-nmba-lions-headed-to-acaa-teams</id>
    <published>2014-06-18T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-19T14:55:40-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The hard work, dedication and commitment to development and fundamentals is starting to pay off for the Northside Minor Basketball Association.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three former NMBA Lions are off to play at the Canadian Collegiate Athletic Association level in 2014-15. Former Leo Hayes High Lions' Sara Ripley will play at Mount Allison University and her teammate Allison Keane will play with the Holland College Hurricanes of Charlottetown. Former NMBAer Emma Blizzard will be with the St. Thomas University Tommies. Blizzard played with the Fredericton High Black Kats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All three played at the bantam level with the NMBA during their minor basketball days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="sara-ripley"&gt;Sara Ripley&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ripley will be a welcome addition to the garnet and gold in Sackville with the Mounties, said head coach Matt Gamblin.The forward played for the 2New Brunswick Canada Summer Games team in Sherbrooke, Que., finishing off a stellar four-year career with the Lions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;'Sara's work-ethic, and blue-chip approach to the game is well known throughout NB high school basketball,' said Gamblin. 'Her rebounding, defence and all-out hustle will translate great in our league and with our brand of basketball at MTA, we are very excited to have Sara joining the Mounties.'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ripley can't wait for the leaves to turn. 'After four years of high school basketball I'm really looking forward to taking my game to the next level,' she said. 'I am very excited to play for Mount A with some girls that I have played with before and with others I have yet to meet.'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="allison-keane"&gt;Allison Keane&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keane, a 5'7'' guard is ready to suit up for the Hurricanes and will enter her first year in the Sport and Leisure Management Program this September.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;'I am so excited to be going into the Sport and Leisure Management Program at Holland College,' said Keane. 'I fell in love with the school and the City of Charlottetown while I was there for a tournament with my high school team.'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The feeling is mutual with the 'Canes. 'Allison choosing Holland College as a student-athlete is a prime example of the importance of showcasing the college through the hosting of championships, tournaments and events to high-school recruits. We're very pleased to have her join us as a student-athlete,' said Albert Roche, Athletics and Recreation Director at Holland College.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keane was the captain of the Leo Hayes varsity basketball team in 2014 and a teammate with Ripley and Blizzard at the Canada Games. She also represented New Brunswick in 2012 on the under-16 provincial team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurricanes head coach Mike Connolly is pleased to have Keane join his roster after garnering attention from several local New Brunswick colleges and universities. 'She is a tough competitor who will bring a real energy on the defensive end,' he said. 'We think she is ready to make a contribution right away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keane, who is working out with former teammates this summer, wants to bring pace to Holland College. 'I like a fast pace, up-tempo game and distributing the ball is my strength as well as shooting beyond the arc,' she said. 'Being gritty and aggressive on defence is what makes the game fun for me.'&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="emma-blizzard"&gt;Emma Blizzard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fredericton basketball fans won't have to look too far to follow Blizzard as she joins perennial CCAA threat St. Thomas and head coach Fred Connors. Blizzard represented New Brunswick on the under-15 and under-17 provincial teams. She was a part of two New Brunswick Interscholastic Athletic Association champion teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;'We like Emma's toughness and defensive focus,' said Connors.  'She is a team-first player who wants to work hard and get better and is strong enough to handle the demands of the program.'&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NMBA Registers Three Summerfest Teams</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/06/17/nmba-registers-three-summerfest-teams"/>
    <id>http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/06/17/nmba-registers-three-summerfest-teams</id>
    <published>2014-06-16T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-19T15:26:38-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Three teams will represent the Northside Minor Basketball Association next month at Basketball New Brunswick's Summerfest tournament at the University of New Brunswick at Saint John.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although UNBSJ houses the bulk of games, the large tournament uses a number of other schools in the City of Saint John to accommodate the demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NMBA will have teams at the Women's Open division, Under-17 Womens' Competition class and Under-15 Girls' Development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone interested in entering a team for the 2014 tournament should contact Carolyn Peppin (carolyn.peppin@basketball.nb.ca) ASAP as many divisions fill very quickly. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="resources"&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.basketball.nb.ca/app/SpecialEvents/BNBSummerfestTournament/tabid/234/language/en-US/Default.aspx"&gt;BNB Summerfest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>NMBA Represented at Basketball Canada Events</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/06/11/nmba-represented-at-basketball-canada"/>
    <id>http://northsidehoops.com/blog/2014/06/11/nmba-represented-at-basketball-canada</id>
    <published>2014-06-10T21:00:00-03:00</published>
    <updated>2014-06-11T22:19:22-03:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's remarkable to think about how many athletes and coaches the Northside Minor Basketball Association has sent to Canadian championships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In its short history, the NMBA has produced a number of players or had players dress in Lions' gear who have played on the national stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year will not be any different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the Basketball Canada age-class Under-15 and Under-17 Championship set for Edmonton in late July, many in the province and Fredericton will be following former Lions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Under-15 girls' team has former NMBA Under-13 player Brook Billings on its roster. The Under-17 boys' team has former Lions Jared Stafford and Leo Titarenko playing for Team N.B.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stafford and Titarenko have a familiar sideline voice to hear. NMBA board member and long-time Leo Hayes High Lions' head coach John Hickey is the head helmsman of the provincial squad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NMBA bantam girls' Division 1 head coach Ryan Chase, who is Hickey's assistant with Leo Hayes, is the head coach of the &lt;abbr title="Basketball New Brunswick"&gt;BNB&lt;/abbr&gt; Under-15 boys' team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both Hickey and Chase coached Team N.B. at last year's Canada Summer Games in Sherbrooke, Que.
This summer's tournament, open this year for the first time to scouts from the &lt;abbr title="National Collegiate Athletic Association"&gt;NCAA&lt;/abbr&gt;, are set for July 25 to July 30 at the Saville Community Sports Centre in Edmonton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Former Lion Taylor Forsythe is a member of the provincial Under-16 girls' team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NMBA is also awaiting word on adding potential players to the &lt;abbr title="Basketball New Brunswick"&gt;BNB&lt;/abbr&gt; Under-14 teams, selected following the &lt;a href="http://basketball.nb.ca/app/AthleteDevelopment/BantamEliteCamp/tabid/141/language/en-US/Default.aspx"&gt;Bantam Elite Camp&lt;/a&gt; in Fredericton in early July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Former Bantam A Lion Micah Williams is in the boys' selection camp. Present Bantam A Lions Lucy Beaumont, Torrie Janes and Kali Wilson will attend the girls' selection camp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Under-14 teams will participate at &lt;a href="http://www.basketball.nb.ca/app/SpecialEvents/BNBSummerfestTournament/tabid/234/language/en-US/Default.aspx"&gt;Summerfest&lt;/a&gt; in Saint John at the Under-15 development level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="tournamentscamps"&gt;Tournaments/Camps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.basketball.ca/national-championship-s15162"&gt;Basketball Canada U15 and U17 Championships&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.basketball.nb.ca/app/SpecialEvents/BNBSummerfestTournament/tabid/234/language/en-US/Default.aspx"&gt;&lt;abbr title="Basketball New Brunswick"&gt;BNB&lt;/abbr&gt; Summerfest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://basketball.nb.ca/app/AthleteDevelopment/BantamEliteCamp/tabid/141/language/en-US/Default.aspx"&gt;&lt;abbr title="Basketball New Brunswick"&gt;BNB&lt;/abbr&gt; Bantam Elite Camp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
